$Cj \; Buresch \qquad \qquad {\it cj@csubj.io} \; \diamond \; {\it linkedin/csubj} \; \diamond \; {\it github/csubj}$

Senior Software Engineer \diamond Infrastructure, Storage, Compute he/him \diamond Seattle, WA

OBJECTIVE	

With almost 10 years in platform/backend SWE and SRE roles at the world's largest consumer and social software companies I've honed a broad and eclectic skillset owning physical and cloud infrastructure, developing automation for and supporting massive distributed storage services. As a recent startup founder and experienced engineer I'm excited for opportunities to develop in new domains and continue following my passion for reliable engineering in my next role developing fault tolerant web-scale software.

EXPERIENCE ____

Senior Software Engineer

Zillow Group, Inc.

July 2023 - Present Seattle, WA

Developing a self-service compute platform for 300+ engineers. In a team of 3 we own observability, deployment pipelines, tooling and automatiom, cloud infrastructure and networking for our client teams.

- King County Search and Rescue Team member since 2024! "So that others may live..."
- Avid mountain climber and adventure traveler! Summitted Mt. Baker, Mt. Shuksan, and Mt. Hood; hiked the Salkantay Trail in Peru!
- 3d Printing enthusiast! I solve my everyday problems with plastic.

Founder hef labs LLC April 2023 - Present Seattle, WA

Early stage startup developing consumer apps. TechStack: Go/Python with Bazel, PostgreSQL, AWS, Typescript + NextJS, Terraform.

Senior Software Engineer

Twitter, Inc. - Blobstore (Distributed KV Object Storage)

Dec 2018 - Nov 2022

Seattle, WA

As a team of 9 we stored more than 70PB of Twitter's media data in an on-prem multi-datacenter eventually consistent distributed system. As the infrastructure lead I was responsible for 8k physical machines (hardware health and lifecycle), service automation, monitoring, tooling and deployments as well as anti-entropy services while also taking feature projects.

Accomplishments

- Designed and implemented on-prem chargeback reporting improving a previously annual and manual process to an automated daily report of network, api usage, storage class, data locality charges. This had immediate impact for internal customers to understand their use-case costs and inform choices to improve their service's COGS.
- Developed an environment of services and orchestrated tasks (Airflow) for infrastructure automation that ensured operators worked safely and independently without affecting service health or causing downtime. This lead to realized opportunities like no-touch deployments on stateful baremetal services and automated hardware failure remediation that eliminated weeks of developer operational toil; tangibly it reduced pages from 90/wk to 4-5/wk and increased deployments from several times a quarter to weekly for the storage tier.
- Compliance automation rolled all machines in less than 25 days with no manual intervention and negligible service impact. As a result Blobstore was consistently in the top 5 of patched fleets across the company.
- Implemented anti-entropy services to scan large metadata dumps, billions of keys processed via MapReduce fed a key-list to repair workers to patch production every week.
- Migrated stateless services from baremetal to Aurora Mesos compute to ease operational burden, improve developer velocity and service reliability as well as cut 6-figures from annual COGS.

• Maintained service monitoring and tooling, system health, system config, loadtesting, capacity planning and oncall.

Primary Languages: Go, Python, Scala, Typescript

Previous Experience: C#, Java, R

Relevant Technologies: Scalding (MapReduce), Airflow, Docker, K8s, Azure/GCP/AWS,

gRPC/thrift, Bazel, Terraform

Education _____

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

2011 - 2015

Spokane, WA

Gonzaga University

Clubs and Activities

Men's Rowing, Div. 1 2011-12 ACM ICPC, PNW 2012, '13, '14

Computer Science Club 2012-15 Math Club 2013-15 Cycling Club 2013-15 WSU Hackathon 2015

Achievements

3rd On-Site, ACM ICPC (PNW) 2013, 2014

Leadership _____

- Mentored two cohorts of new grads and interns with weekly 1:1's, adhoc sessions and code reviews to help them ramp up into Twitter Engineering!
- Ambassador for Twitter Seattle 2021-2022. Responsible for planning events, creating opportunities for colleagues to socialize in a hybrid environment, as well as assisting onsite operations management.

Extra-Curricular Activities _____

- King County Search and Rescue Team member since 2024! "So that others may live!"
- Avid mountain climber and adventure traveler! Summitted Mt. Baker, Mt. Shuksan, and Mt. Hood; hiked the Salkantay Trail in Peru!
- 3d Printing enthusiast! I solve my everyday problems with plastic.